claires.co.uk 2018-06-09

# Privacy Policy | Claire's US

Last updated and is effective as of 15 May, 2018

This Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) applies to Claire’s Stores, Inc. and the businesses operating under the Claire’s brand that are owned or controlled by Claire’s Stores Inc. or under common control or ownership with Claire’s Stores, Inc., the website claires.com, mobile applications, and other interactive features or protocols that link to this Privacy Policy (the “Site”). This Privacy Policy applies to consumers and visitors of the Site and Claire’s stores in the United States only. This Privacy Policy explains our practices and governs the use of personal information Claire’s collects from you or about you through the Site, its mobile applications, written or oral communications, when you visit its retail stores, or from other sources, including job application systems and careers sites.

Claire’s is a US-based jewelry and accessories retailer headquartered at 2400 West Central Road, Hoffman Estates, Illinois 60192, USA.

**By further browsing the Site, creating an account or registering on the Site, contacting Claire’s customer service, or applying for a position of employment with Claire’s you agree to this Privacy Policy and consent to the collection and use of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. Please also review the[Terms of Use](http://www.claires.com/us/ts-and-cs.html), which governs your use of the Site and any content you submit to the Site.**

We take data privacy very seriously and work super hard to protect your personal information. When collecting and using your personal information we comply with the US and EU privacy laws then in effect and applicable to Claire’s; where our global presence subjects us to stricter requirements of personal data protection laws and regulations of a given state, we commit to comply with those requirements. Please take a look at what we do with your information and the choices you can make about how it’s collected and used. 

  * Why we collect your personal information
  * What information we collect
  * Shopping
  * Information We Collect Automatically
  * Marketing
  * Customer Service Calls
  * Mobile Applications
  * Social Media
  * Job Applications
  * How we collect information
  * Personal Information from Children
  * Use of Cookies
  * Use of web beacons, clear-GIFs, pixel tags and Javascript
  * Widgets and Server Logs
  * Search queries on our website
  * Information for business partners and suppliers
  * How we use the information we collect
  * When and how we share your information with others
  * Your rights & choices about the information we collect
  * Retention of your personal information
  * Transfer and Processing of Information in the United States
  * Links
  * Security
  * Notice to California Residents
  * Questions / Changes in Policy

## WHY WE COLLECT INFORMATION

In this Privacy Policy, “personal information” means any information that can be used to identify you. This can include your name and last name, address, username, email address, photographs, but can also include your IP address, your geolocation, and shopping preferences and interests. We collect personal information because it is necessary to enable us to deliver products and services. For example, if you order a product, we need to have information such as your billing address, product choice, delivery information, and payment processing information. In addition, your personal information helps us communicate to you the latest products, special offers, and information and events about which you might like to hear if you choose to. 

We also collect your personal information to help us design and deliver the Site operations, and to deliver targeted advertisements to you. We also may correlate your personal information obtained from you with information from other sources, which may help us to develop a more targeted user profile concerning you and/or your demographic information. For example, if you provide us with your personal information, we may cross-check that against information that might be otherwise available through other entities with whom we have business relationships in order to develop a more in-depth demographic profile of you. Similarly, we may process personal information to target specific items of interest to you. 

We know that everyone is busy, and nobody likes their email cluttered up. As such we will only send you marketing messages if you choose to receive them from us. If you decide that you no longer want to receive our marketing emails you can opt-out at any time by selecting and clicking ‘Unsubscribe’ or email us at [dataprotection@claires.com](mailto:dataprotection@claires.com). 

## WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We may collect personal information at every point of interaction with you. The following generally describes the type of information we may collect about you.

## SHOPPING

When you shop on the Site, we will collect the personal information necessary to process your order, such as your name and last name, e-mail address, shipping address, payment information (including credit card number and/or debit card number) and billing address.

At your option, you may also provide demographic information (such as your gender or age), but it is not required.

If you create an account on the Site, you will be required to give certain information such as name and email address. We will collect information about your purchases and payment methods, as well as the shipping addresses that you add to your address book, in order to make future shopping experiences faster and more convenient. We will use this information to process your transaction and dispatch your order. Any data that is necessary to process your order constitutes transactional data, and if you refuse to provide it we will not be able to process your order.

When you shop at Claire’s store, your payment information (such as your payment card number and other card information) is collected to process the purchase. Also, in some of the high-risk stores Claire’s uses video cameras to deter shoplifting, and, therefore, while you are on certain Claire’s premises video of you may be captured. 

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT AUTOMATICALLY 

We do not automatically collect your home address, email address, telephone number, and product preferences unless you voluntarily input this information, such as during a registration or ordering process, or when you submit questions or comments, request information, or participate in online surveys, contests, promotions or other activities. However, as is true of most websites, the Site collects certain information automatically and stores it in log files.

In addition to any personal information or other information that you choose to submit to the Site, we and our third-party service providers (including content and analytics providers and advertising companies) may use a variety of technologies that automatically or passively collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with the Site or one of our advertisements or other content elsewhere online (“Usage Information”). Usage Information may include the browser you are using, the URL that referred you to our Site, all of the areas within our Site that you visit, and the time of the visit, among other information. Our systems may also automatically gather information about the search terms you use on our Site and the links you select from within our Site to other areas of the Web or elsewhere online. In addition, we may collect your IP address or other unique identifier of your computer, cell phone, or other device used to access the Site (collectively referred to as a “Device Identifier”). A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer, your cell phone, or other device used to access the Site, and our computers identify your device by its Device Identifier. Usage Information may be non-identifying or may be associated with you and therefore identifiable. Whenever we associate Usage Information or a Device Identifier with you, as an individual and identifiable person, we will treat it as personal information.

Note that your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to websites and online services you visit. There is no consensus among industry participants as to what “Do Not Track” means in this context. Like many websites and online services, the Site currently does not alter its practices when it receives a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/). 

## MARKETING

Only when you consent, we use your personal information to send you marketing materials, to conduct surveys, contests, sweepstakes, and to award prizes. Personal information processed for marketing purposes includes your name and last name, home address, email, and contact phone number. We may request additional information to participate in contests and surveys such as your photos, personal opinions, preferences, interests, and information about your family members. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose your information. Your contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. We provide marketing communications via email, postal mail, online advertising, push notifications, social media, app messaging, and other means. 

## CUSTOMER SERVICE CALLS

Certain customer experience and/or transactions may involve you calling us at 1-800-CLAIRES or emailing at [customerservice@claires.com](mailto:customerservice@claires.com). To handle your requests and provide high-level customer service we need to collect your personal information such as your name and last name, phone number, and transaction details. We may also record our phone conversation for training and quality assurance purposes. 

## MOBILE APPLICATIONS

Claire’s makes available mobile applications for download on various mobile devices. When downloading these applications, you may be asked for certain personal information such as name and last name, email address, and phone number. If you are using one of our mobile apps, we may also collect information about the way you use our app. 

## SOCIAL MEDIA

The Site may permit you to interact with a third-party site or service, such as enabling you to “like” Claire’s on another site or “share” content from the Site with other sites (a “Social Networking Service”). If you choose to “like” or “share” content or to otherwise post information from or via the Site to a Social Networking Service, that information may be publicly displayed, and the third party may have access to certain information about you and your use of the Site. Similarly, if you interact with us through a Social Networking Service, we may have access to information about you (for example, if you “like” or “follow” our page on a third-party site). Please note that if you mention or comment on Claire’s or the Site in your post to a third-party platform, the third-party platform may allow us to publish your post on the Site.

You may also choose to use a social media tool offered by a third party, but available on the Site (such as posting a review or logging into the Site with your username and password for another site, such as the “Facebook Connect” feature). Use of such a feature may allow us to collect (or the third party to share) information about you, including your personal information. Information about you, including your name and profile photo, may be shown to other users of the Site if you are logged in through the Site or through a third-party website or service or if you have previously posted content to the Site while logged in. When you choose to use a social media tool available through the Site, you may be opting to link your activity on our Site with that third-party tool or service, which may then collect information about your visits to our Site and, if sharing function is enabled, may publish that activity to your profile with that third party. For example, when you link your Facebook account to the Site using “Facebook Connect”, your likes, product reviews, and “Wish List” additions will be shared on your Facebook account unless you disable that sharing.

In addition, we may receive information about you if other users of a third-party website give us access to their profiles and you are one of their “connections” or information about you is otherwise accessible through your “connections” web page, profile page, or similar page on a social networking or other third-party website or interactive service.

The information we collect is subject to this Privacy Policy. The information collected and stored by the third parties remains subject to the third parties’ privacy practices, including whether the third parties continue to share information with us, the types of information shared, and your choices with regards to what is visible to others on that third-party website and service. The third party may allow you to remove the application or feature, in which case we will no longer collect information about you through the application or feature, but we may retain the information previously collected. 

## JOB APPLICATIONS

If you choose to apply for a position of employment with Claire’s, we process your personal information, including name and last name, date of birth, address, contact information, login and password for users of clairescareers.com, resume, cover letter, work experience, education, professional and work-related licenses, and audio and video recordings of interviews. You may choose to provide other information as part of your application. We do not require and will instruct you to abstain from voluntarily providing the information regarding your sexual orientation, race, ethnic origin, political opinions, religious and philosophical beliefs, and trade union membership unless the local employment laws require otherwise. 

## HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION

We collect information in three primary ways:

1\. You give us information: We collect information from you when you sign up to receive marketing, purchase a service or a product from us, or when you interact with us about a product or service we offer or provide. 

2\. We collect information automatically: We automatically collect certain types of personal information when you visit the Site or use products and services. For example, we automatically collect various types of technical information when you use the Site as described in this Privacy Policy.

3\. We collect information from other sources: We may obtain information about you from outside sources. For example, we may obtain commercially available information about you from third parties, such as demographic information for advertising and marketing purposes. We may also receive information from third parties who provide third-party tracking services through web-beacons as otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy. 

## PERSONAL INFORMATION FROM CHILDREN

We recognize the importance of children’s safety and privacy. We do not knowingly collect personal information from or about children under the age of 13 without their parent’s or legal guardian’s consent. 

If you are under the age of 13, please seek the consent of your parent or legal guardian for your personal data to be collected by Claire’s when browsing this Site. You will be able to create an account, place orders, and purchase goods and/ or services on the Site only if you verify your age. 

_PARENTAL PARTICIPATION._ As a parent or legal guardian, please do not allow your children to submit personal information without your permission. If you believe that we might process personal information about your child without your consent, please contact us at [dataprotection@claires.com](mailto:dataprotection@claires.com). 

## USE OF COOKIES

The Site uses cookies. Cookies are bits of electronic information that a website may transfer to a visitor's computer to identify specific information about the visitor's visits to a website. The Site uses a browser feature known as a cookie, which assigns a unique identification to your computer. Cookies are typically stored on your computer's hard drive and are used to help track clicks as you go through the pages within the Site.

Our cookies do not collect any personally identifiable information, such as your name, address or payment details. We may also use cookies to tell us whether you have previously visited the Site. We also use cookies which may be set by third parties with whom we have entered into agreements which may enable us to obtain other information about you as may be available from those third parties, such as demographic data about you.

You can set your browser not to accept cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the opportunity to decide whether or not to accept it. You may also use commonly available tools in your browser to remove cookies which may have been placed onto your computer. If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that store cookies. Alternatively you may wish to visit www.aboutcookies.org which contains comprehensive information on how to manage cookies on a wide variety of browsers. However, please note that if you disable the use of cookies on your computer, some functionality of the Site will not work, however you will still be able to browse and shop on the Site.

Below we explain the types of cookies that may be used on our Site: 

Below we explain the types of cookies that may be used on our Site: 

(a) **'Strictly Necessary' cookies.** These cookies are essential for the operation of the website and enable you to access certain site features. Without these cookies, we would be unable to provide you with the online services you request. These cookies do not track where you have been on the internet and do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing purposes.

(b) **Functional cookies.** Functional cookies are used to recognize you when you return to the website. They also remember your preferences (such as your username, language and region) on our Site and enable us to personalize our content for you. The information collected by these cookies is usually anonymized, so we cannot identify you personally. Functional cookies do not track your internet usage or gather information which could be used for selling advertising, but they do help with serving advertising.

(c) **Analytical cookies.** Analytical cookies are used to monitor the performance of our Site. For example, they allow us to recognize and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our Site when they are using it. The information provided by these cookies allows us to analyze patterns of user behavior and we use that information to enhance user experience or identify areas of the Site which may require maintenance. All of the information collected by these cookies is anonymous and is only used for statistical purposes.

(d) **Targeting and advertising cookies.** These cookies may be placed on your device by us or by trusted third parties. They remember that you have visited our Site and use that information to provide you with advertising which is tailored to your interests. This is often called online behavioral advertising (OBA) and involves the monitoring of interests based upon web browsing history. Your web browsing history can be used to infer things about you (for example, your age, gender etc.), and this information may also be used to make advertising on websites more relevant to you. Although behavioral advertising cookies can track your activity around the internet they cannot identify you personally, even if you are signed in to our Site. Without these cookies, online advertisements you encounter will be less relevant to you and your interests. If you would like more information about OBA, including how to opt-out of these cookies, please visit www.youronlinechoices.com.

We will not use FLASH cookies, unless you are specifically notified that we intend to use them for a specific service, and you are given the opportunity to opt-out from receiving such cookies. FLASH cookies are cookies that are placed on your computer that are not removed through normal browser management tools, but the developer of the FLASH programming language currently has an on-line management tool to allow you to remove these FLASH cookies.

When you browse the Site some cookies may be set by third parties, over which we have no control. When you visit a page with embedded third-party content, the service provider may set their own cookies on your device. You may also encounter third party cookies resulting from our use of third party services, which help us monitor traffic on the Site. We do not control the use of these cookies and you should refer to the relevant third-party websites for more information. 

## USE OF WEB BEACONS, CLEAR-GIFS, PIXEL TAGS AND JAVASCRIPT

We also use other technologies such as “pixel tags” (also called “action pixels”, “web beacons” or “clear gifs”) and/or JavaScript plug-ins placed on the Site and in our emails to you.

These web beacons and plug-ins are small graphic images (typically that you cannot see) or code on a website or in an email message which are used for such things as recording web pages and advertisements clicked-on by a user, or for tracking the performance of email marketing campaigns. These devices help us analyze our customers' online behavior and measure the effectiveness of the Site and advertising. We also work with third-party service providers that help us track, collect, and analyze this information. Third-party entities with whom we have agreements may place these devices on the Site and/or in e-mails sent to you to use information obtained from them such as pages viewed, items purchased, e-mails opened and items upon which you may click in e-mails. These third-party providers may also place cookies onto your computer. Those third-party cookies may enable us to obtain aggregate demographic information and user statistics about you and your preferences from these third-party sources as well as our information we have about you. 

## WIDGETS AND SERVER LOGS

A “widget” is generally an application that can be embedded in a web page. Widgets can provide real-time information to the page. Widgets are often provided by third parties and we may provide widgets on the Site. Widgets may enable the third parties that provide them to collect data about users visiting the Site. We may also obtain information shared with us through the providers of these widgets.

A web “server log” is a record of activity created by a computer that delivers certain web pages to your browser. Certain activities that you perform on the Site may record information in server logs, such as if you enter a search term into a search box located on the Site. The server log may record the search term, or the link you clicked on to bring you to the Site. The server log may also record information about your browser, such as your IP address and the cookies set on your browser. 

## SEARCH QUERIES ON OUR WEBSITE

We may provide you with options to search for information on the Site. If you enter information in a search query box, we may store that information and we may aggregate that information with other information we may have about the browser and/or IP address from which the search query originated.

## INFORMATION FOR BUSINESS PARTNERS AND SUPPLIERS

If you represent a business partner or a supplier of Claire’s we may need to collect and process your personal information to administer and develop the business relationship with you or the party you represent, to perform contractual obligations, to conduct satisfaction surveys, and to monitor compliance. Claire’s may need to collect all the information that can be found on your business card or in your email signature with a few exceptions: first name, last name, job title, employer name, work address, business email, and business phone number. We may share your personal information with third parties that provide services to Claire’s, but we do not sell or rent your personal information or share it for marketing purposes. 

## HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use your information for many purposes, such as to: (i) deliver the products or services you order, including processing orders, returns and third party payments; (ii) analyze trends and conduct research about improving our products and services; (iii) provide support and respond to questions from customers and the Site visitors; (iv) improve the Site, products or services; (v) learn about customers’ needs; (vi) contact consumers for research, informational, and marketing purposes, including customizing our product recommendations to you based upon your information and purchases; (vii) track traffic patterns and the Site usage; (viii) enable online ordering and provide customer service with respect to such orders; (ix) correlate information with other commercially available information to identify demographics and preferences to assist us in our marketing efforts; (x) provide specific relevant marketing, promotional, or other information to you; (xi) address information security and/or privacy practices control, network functioning, engineering, and troubleshooting issues; (xii) investigate claims and/or legal actions, violations of our policies and procedures, and compliance with relevant applicable laws and legal process; (xiii) comply with law, or based on our reasonable belief that it is necessary to conform or comply with the law, or otherwise to disclose information to the agencies concerned to prevent fraud, to reduce credit risks, to cooperate with police and other governmental authorities, or to protect the rights and freedoms of individuals, property and safety of visitors to Claire’s stores, the Site, and of the public in general.

## WHEN AND HOW WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION WITH OTHERS

We may also share personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information externally with third-party service providers that have a need to know your personal information in order for us to accept and fulfill your order, provide services requested by you or comply with applicable law or regulation. This might include, but is not necessarily limited to the companies that handle our order dispatch service, pay our delivery company, business entities that provide e-mail address management and communication contact services, network equipment and application management providers and hosting entities, credit and debit card payment gateways and processors and the issuing and acquiring banks involved in the funds settlement procedures necessary to charge your cards or financial accounts, entities which obtain information such as demographic information which might be aggregated with information we have about you, judicial, administrative and/or legal or financial accounting providers in the event that information must be reviewed or released in response to civil and/or criminal investigations, claims, lawsuits, or if we are subject to judicial or administrative process (such as an injunction) to release your information or to prosecute or defend legal actions, and other service providers which may be involved in the other types of services and activities otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy. In the cases where it is required by data protection legislation, we will enter into written agreements with these third parties to place contractual restrictions on these third parties from further transmitting your personal data and the treatment of said data outside of the uses and processing necessary to fulfill their contracts with us. We will only provide these third parties with the information which they need to carry out their jobs and to the extent necessary to perform contractual obligations. 

Some elements on the Site, such as any sponsored links advertising, are supplied to us by third parties under contract. We may supply some of the information we collect from you to those third parties so that they can provide those elements for display. We may share the following information with such third parties: (a) your Internet Protocol (IP) address; (b) the address of the last URL you visited prior to clicking through to the Site; (c) your browser and platform type; (d) your browser language; (e) the data in any undeleted cookies that your browser previously accepted from us; and (f) the search queries or word look-ups you submit. 

## YOUR RIGHTS & CHOICES ABOUT THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

It is important that you are in position to control your personal information. At Claire’s we are committed to provide you with control over your personal information that you share with us. To the extent allowed by applicable law, you have the following rights with respect to your personal information: 

  * Right to confirm whether we maintain any personal information concerning you in our systems and databases; 
  * Right to receive a copy of personal information that you provided to us; 
  * Right to request an amendment or update to any inaccurate personal information that we maintain about you in our systems and databases; 
  * Right to request restrictions on how we use and process your personal information; 
  * Right to revoke authorizations given to us on how to use and share your personal information; 
  * Right to object to using your personal information for certain purposes, including direct marketing and profiling; 
  * Right to request us to delete your personal information from our systems and databases. 

It is important that you are in position to control your personal information. At Claire’s we are committed to provide you with control over your personal information that you share with us. To the extent allowed by applicable law, you have the following rights with respect to your personal information: 

Please be aware that it is not always possible to completely delete or erase all your personal information from our systems and databases without some residual data backups because we need to comply with legal obligations, necessity to perform contracts, resolve disputes or for other legitimate reasons. We may also be unable to delete your transactional data related to your purchases and returns because we need to keep these records as long as required by the applicable law. We will process all the requests within 30 days from receipt or within such other time as specified by applicable law. Such requests should be submitted to [dataprotection@claires.com](mailto:dataprotection@claires.com). For verification purposes and to protect your confidentiality, we can only respond to the requests sent from an email address that you provided to us or used for registering an account on the Site. 

If you have a registered account with Claire’s and would like to update or delete your contact information, please visit the ‘My Account’ section and update your personal information details. 

_OPT-OUT FROM MARKETING._ You have the right to request us to stop processing your personal information for marketing purposes. We will inform you (before collecting your personal information) if we intend to use your personal information for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by refraining from checking certain boxes or providing an email address on the forms we use to collect your personal information for marketing purposes. Alternatively, you can contact us to withdraw your marketing consent at any time.

If you elected to receive marketing materials from us and prefer to no longer receive any marketing materials from us, you may opt-out at any time by using the unsubscribe link located in our e-mails or by sending an email to [dataprotection@claires.com](mailto:dataprotection@claires.com). Opt-out requests can take up to 30 days to be effective. 

We may also use your personal information to contact you in ways other than e-mail or regular mail, such as via telephone number and/or mobile messaging and texts to your mobile phone or through SMS. When you provide your mobile number to Claire’s to receive marketing materials, you agree to receive messages from Claire’s on your mobile phone. The text messages may include, but are not limited to, updates, alerts and exclusive offers. If you sign up to receive SMS or MMS messages from Claire’s, you may unsubscribe from any SMS or MMS messages received by replying “STOP”. 

If you have installed our mobile app and you wish to stop receiving push notifications, you can change the settings either on your mobile device or through the app. You can stop all further collection of information by our mobile app by uninstalling the mobile app. 

## RETENTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We retain personal information about you for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in the Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by applicable law. For example, we are required to keep your basic personal information (name, address, and contact details) under the tax law. Your personal information shared by you for direct marketing purposes will be kept with us until you notify us (by opting out) that you no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us. 

## TRANSFER AND PROCESSING OF INFORMATION IN THE UNITED STATES

Claire’s is a United States corporation. Information we collect from you will be transferred and processed in the United States. Although access to the Site is available around the world, use and enjoyment of the Site is governed and operated in accordance with the laws of the United States and the United Kingdom. Claire’s makes no representations that the Site is governed or operated in accordance with the law of any other state. If you are located outside the United States, please be aware that personal information you provide and/ or collected by Claire’s may be transferred to and processed in the United States and the United Kingdom. 

When visiting the Site your connection will be through and to servers located in the United States and the United Kingdom. All information you receive from us will be created on servers located in the United States and the United Kingdom, and all information you provide will be maintained on web servers and systems located in the United States and the United Kingdom. By using the Site and/or submitting information to us, you specifically consent to the transfer of your information to the facilities and servers in the United States and the United Kingdom, and to those with whom we may share your information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

## LINKS

For your convenience, the Site may contain links to third party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices, advertising, products, or the content of such third-party websites. None of the links should be deemed to imply that we endorse or have any affiliation with the links. Please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that Claire’s does not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. 

## SECURITY

We believe in providing a safe and secure experience for all of our customers and the Site visitors. To that end we have implemented security measures to protect the information collected from you. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers and on the servers of cloud-based service providers. The computers and servers on which we store personal information are kept in a secure environment. While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Payment transactions may be undertaken by third party service providers and will be encrypted using industry standard SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access your online account, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Every employee accessing systems containing your personal information has a separate unique username and password. Access to your personal information is limited to those employees who require such access to perform their job duties. In addition, we train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your personal information. We commit to taking appropriate disciplinary measures to enforce our employees’ privacy responsibilities. 

Although we make every effort to protect the personal information which you provide to us, please note that no data transmitted over the Internet or stored and utilized for business purposes can be guaranteed to be completely secure. No security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot ensure that information you share on the Site will not become publicly available. As such, you acknowledge and accept that we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to the Site and that any such transmission is at your own risk. You can reduce these risks by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up to date antivirus software. 

## NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

Pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as “Shine the Light” law, Claire’s may share personal information of California residents with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes only with respect to the personal information provided by such California residents to Claire’s when obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household and when opt-in consent for such data sharing is obtained. Our California customers are entitled (a) to request and obtain from us, one time per calendar year, a list of categories of personal information we shared, if any, during the immediately prior calendar year with other businesses for their own direct marketing purposes and their addresses; (b) to opt-out of any such information sharing with third parties for direct marketing purposes at any time by sending an email at [dataprotection@claires.com](mailto:dataprotection@claires.com), please include your full name, e-mail address, and postal address in your message.

## QUESTIONS / CHANGES IN POLICY

If you have questions or concerns with respect to our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [dataprotection@claires.com](mailto:dataprotection@claires.com). We reserve the right to change or amend this Privacy Policy at any time, without prior notice to you; in such event, we will post the amended Privacy Policy on the Site. We may email you to notify about the material changes thereto, but you should check our Site to see the current Privacy Policy in effect.
